<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	<!-- generator="WordPress/6.6.2" created="2024-11-11 11:23" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Do I Care About Equality?</title>
	<link>https://myblog-1gt63hoo0o.live-website.com</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 11:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>es</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://myblog-1gt63hoo0o.live-website.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://myblog-1gt63hoo0o.live-website.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author>
		<wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id>
		<wp:author_login><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_login>
		<wp:author_email><![CDATA[brainresetting@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email>
		<wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name>
		<wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name>
		<wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name>
	</wp:author>

	<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>

	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Some ideas about inequality]]></title>
		<link>https://myblog-1gt63hoo0o.live-website.com/hello-world/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 11:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://myblog-1gt63hoo0o.live-website.com/?p=1</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If there are fewer rich people that own more portion of the wealth whilst the majority of people gets less percentage of the wealth, it means that everybody is producing for those rich people. If you believe that it's wrong to redistribute wealth to some extent, you might reconsider your beliefs. If you think I am talking communism, please heal whatever wounds communism has done to you and come back to the conversation. No one is talking about communism here.</p>

<p>If technology allows us to be way more productive why don't we work less? Let's say that at a certain point in time, there is a business that has 10 workers. It's a group of 10 people making enough money for all of the 10. Then they decide to buy a machine/software that helps them do their work twice as fast. If this group was a group of equal coworkers, most likely they might decide to work half the time and enjoy their free time. Now, when this is a company with a boss and 9 employees, is it to be considered normal that the boss decided to fire 5 employees and add their former salary to his? Sure, it's something he can do if he wants, but morally there can be a limit to this. If the boss knows that those 5 employees will not be able to find any other income source, wouldn't it be immoral for him to let them starve while there is plenty of wealth for all of them?</p>

<p>This example is a bit extreme, but let's go to a different situation. After 5 employees are fired, they need to do something else. But... let's imagine that the first 10 workers were producing for their subsistence. They didn't need to do anything else in order to have food, shelter, clothing and even some commodities. What are the 5 jobless people going to do now that the technical advancement has made it possible for the boss to fire them? They don't really need to do anything from a materialistic and survival point of view as there is enough... except they don't have access to it. The boss is keeping it. Therefore they need to go back to survival mode and restart from the bottom. Or they can decide to steal. There is enough so eventually stealing is easier than working from scratch, especially if they have to compete with the already established 5 workers + tech company. Or even killing the boss. Not that these ideas are morally better, but as understandable as it would be that the boss wants to have more, it would be understandable that the 5 ex-workers had a feeling of injustice to be satisfied. They also have time and the power of five men. But let's not get violent. Let's imagine that the 5 ex-workers will find a way to start their own activity and thanks to their previous expertise, build a similar company that also has a PC and they are able to cover their needs as before... would it make sense that 10 people are working twice as needed just because of the greed of a single person? If 9 people work double because one is wanting to have more, is it ethical for that one person? Is it not rather stupid for them to allow it? We come back to violence, but to some point, not considering your peers as equals is somehow violent. Humanity has never really been against violence anyway, and that's why I'm more talking about being reasonable and things making sense.</p>

<p>Now, would there be conflict if the technical progress' benefit is shared among the whole community? Let's see another case: The boss sees that now that we have a computer, we can work less time and tell the employees to reorganize their times so that they can better enjoy their free time. As there is a potential to free 50% of their previous working time, he tells them to keep doing their former work 50% of the time, save 10% for working time where they will think of new ideas to improve their situation and the left 40% is for them to enjoy life.</p>

<p>With the 50% of work, they maintain their prior stable economic situation, plus are investing a 10% in R&D and instead of feeling injustice, the workers feel belonging and loyalty. The boss didn't win a 500% salary increase but won a 40% free time, happier workers (that translate to more stability in his company) and the potential for further improvements (that can also translate to a better future). Even, coming to the topic of inequality, I don't think anyone in the company would complain if the boss takes a reasonably bigger part of the benefits, as he is the one who started the enterprise, risked his capital and is the mind behind their own capacity to produce their survival means.</p>

<p>We could picture a situation where the extra effort that the PC releases is divided like that: workers keep 75% of their work, a part is dedicated to further improvements and the rest goes for the boss. It's still unequal, but it's reasonable and more than that: is humane. No greedy firing. No useless extra work.</p>

<p>Maybe it's time we review our economic models, as they are based on producing more and more. When there is enough, we can't continue in the producing mindset. It simply doesn't make sense. Are we stupid?</p>
		]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2024-02-03 11:43:31]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2024-02-03 11:43:31]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2024-02-08 17:27:42]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2024-02-08 17:27:42]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hello-world]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>

